## Ivo Gatzinski

San Diego, CA 92122 | ivo.gatzinski@outlook.com | 619-352-0538

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivo-gatzinski/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ivo-gatzinski/</a>
Portfolio: <a href="https://ivo-gatzinski.github.io/portfolio/">https://ivo-gatzinski.github.io/portfolio/</a>

GitHub: https://github.com/Ivo-Gatzinski/

#### **Summary**

Multilingual, multicultural, multidisciplinary Full Stack Web Developer with 3 years of experience. Collaborative, attentive, and compassionate listener who meets concrete needs of diverse viewpoints. Sensitive to others' perspectives, having lived in 6 countries on 4 continents. Fluent in Bulgarian and Russian; moderate French; basic Japanese. Earned Certificate in Full Stack Web Design by UCSD. (Grade: A)

#### **Competencies**

- Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, JAVA, Python
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB, IndexedDB, Apollo, GraphQL
- Frameworks: React, Handlebars, Node, Express, Mongoose, Sequelize, Spring, Thymeleaf

# Projects (2021)

"Healthy Pets" - Vet & Pet communication portal.

- Tools: JavaScript, React.js, GraphQL, Apollo, MongoDB, Module.CSS, HTML
- GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/elenaliu0415/healthy-pets/">https://github.com/elenaliu0415/healthy-pets/</a>
- Deployed App: https://healthy-pets-copypaste.herokuapp.com/

"Magic 8 Ball" - Combat decision fatigue!

- Tools: JavaScript, MySQL, Handlebars.js, MDBootstrap CSS, HTML
- GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/lvo-Gatzinski/magic-8-ball/">https://github.com/lvo-Gatzinski/magic-8-ball/</a>
- Deployed App: <a href="https://magic8-ezi.herokuapp.com/">https://magic8-ezi.herokuapp.com/</a>

"Adopt a Furry Buddy" - Search for Adoptable Dogs.

- Tools: JavaScript, Server-Side APIs, CSS, HTML
- GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/lvo-Gatzinski/adoption-connection/">https://github.com/lvo-Gatzinski/adoption-connection/</a>
- Deployed App: <a href="https://ivo-gatzinski.github.io/adoption-connection/">https://ivo-gatzinski.github.io/adoption-connection/</a>

#### **Experience**

Teaching Assistant for Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp edX Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, UCSD Extension, San Diego, CA

2022-Present

- Taught Full Stack Web Development to a diverse team of students
- Tutored diverse students in JavaScript, CSS, HTML, MySQL, MongoDB, IndexedDB, Apollo, GraphQL, React, Handlebars, Node, Express, Mongoose, Sequelize
- Designed active learning strategies for quickly improving programming skills for beginners

Adjunct Faculty in Political Science

Miramar College Department of Political Science, San Diego, CA

2019-Present

- Taught U.S. government, introductory and comparative politics, theory, economics, social science research, and academic writing via individual tutoring, on-site, hybrid, and online instruction, using various online learning platforms, such as Blackboard, Canvas, Aplia, Connect, etc.
- Tutored diverse students to enable holistic growth in learning capacities
- Designed active learning strategies for investigating politics and society objectively

Adjunct Faculty in Economics

Southwestern College Department of Economics, Chula Vista, CA

2016-2017

Taught economics, and relevant social science research, academic writing, reading, and math skills

## Tutor in Social Sciences, Humanities, and ESL Grossmont College Tutoring Center, El Cajon, CA

2013-2016

- Coached diverse students in economics, sociology, political science, history, research, and writing
- Responded with sensitivity and compassion to coordinate accessibility accommodations
- Taught interdisciplinary material clearly and accessibly to diverse learners and audiences
- Collaborated with staff and faculty to design and administer tutoring services and workshops

#### Southwestern College Academic Success Center, Chula Vista, CA

2016

• Tutored diverse ESL students in academic writing, English, social sciences, and basic math skills

# Adjunct Faculty in Political Science

### Grossmont College Department of Political Economy

2013-2016

- Taught U.S. government, introductory and comparative politics, theory, economics, social science research, and academic writing via individual tutoring, on-site, hybrid, and online instruction, using various online learning platforms, such as Blackboard, Canvas, Aplia, Connect, etc.
- Tutored diverse students to enable holistic growth in learning capacities
- Constructed and applied criteria to measure, assess, monitor, and report student learning outcomes
- Engaged diverse learners and audiences by translating complex ideas and academic research clearly and accessibly into ordinary language in lectures, seminars, and workshops
- Designed active learning strategies for investigating politics and society objectively
- Resolved misinterpretations, complaints, conflicts, and cultural frictions between diverse students, responding with sensitivity and compassion to complex needs

# Adjunct Faculty in Sociology & Political Science National University

2013-2017

- Taught sociology of gender, race, class, economics, and family; social theory; introduction to sociology; introduction to politics, comparative politics, U.S. government; social science research design, on-site, hybrid, and online, with variety of learning platforms, e.g. Blackboard, eCollege, Canvas, etc.
- Met unique needs of working adult veterans from complex and diverse backgrounds
- Mediated verbal and body-language misunderstandings from diverse student viewpoints
- Clearly explicated complex material for working adults in highly accelerated, intensive curriculum
- Facilitated respectful, fluid discussions for the scientific study of sensitive political and social topics
- Compiled and used various criteria, databases, platforms to measure and evaluate learning outcomes

#### **Education**

•	Certificate in Full Stack Web Development – UCSD Bootcamp	2021
•	Doctor of Philosophy Candidate in Political Science – UC San Diego	2003-2012
•	Master's in Political Science – UC San Diego	2005
•	Bachelor's in Economics – Amherst College, Magna Cum Laude, Phi Beta Kappa	2002